我刚撞见凯西光着身体
I just saw Kathy naked.
真是酷刑
It was like torture.
要是你去打仗被俘 你就有福了
If we go to war and you're captured,you're in for a surprise.
事情越来越糟
It keeps getting worse.
爱上室友的女朋友已经够糟了
It bad enough that I'm in love with my roommate's girlfriend.
而且我觉得她知道
By the way,I think she knows
每次我们共处一室 气氛就很诡异紧张
Every time we're in the same room,there's weird energy between us.
就当我疯了 但我觉得她也喜欢我
Call me crazy,but I think she likes me too.
现在我又看到她的裸体
And now I have seen her naked.
她穿着衣服 我还能想像她全身长满烂疮
At least with her clothes on I could imagine her body was covered in boils.
结果没有，她很光滑
But there are no boils. She's smooth.
很光滑
Smooth!
-大家看到他的长袍走光了吗？ -上帝啊
-Could everyone see up his robe? -Oh,my God!
本集播出：“钱德过线了”
The One Where Chandler Crosses the Line
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
拿去
-Here you go.
我待会打给你 好
-I'll call you later.Great!
那是谁？
Hey,hey. Who was that?
那是凯希，我们晚上要约会
Casey. We're going out tonight.
约会？哇
Going out? Wow!
你跟凯西分手了？真可惜
It didn't work out with Kathy? Bummer.
没有啊，我们很好
No,things are fine.
我跟她吃饭之前要先跟凯希吃
I'm having a late meal with her after an early one with Casey.
什么？ 最疯狂的是我刚吃完一整个披萨
-What? -Yeah.The craziest thing is,I just ate a whole pizza myself.
慢着，你要跟凯西见面？
You're going out with Kathy!
对，你干嘛这么不安？
Yeah. Why are you upset?
我是…
Well,I'm upset...
为了你
...for you.
不断跟美女追求性爱 一定很空虚
Sex with an endless line of beautiful women must be unfulfilling.
那又怎样？我们又不是唯一的
What's the big deal? It's not like we're exclusive.
乔伊
Look,Joey.
凯西显然无法满足你的心灵
Kathy's clearly not fulfilling your emotional needs.
但是凯希…
But,Casey....
我虽然只看到她的后脑勺
Granted,I just saw the back of her head.
但是我感觉得到她聪明风趣
But I got this sense that she's smart and funny...
能捉到你的心
...and gets you.
光看后脑勺就知道这么多？
You got all that from the back of her head?
你该定下来了
I think it's time for you to settle down.
做个选择，选一条“路”
Make a choice. Pick a lane.
谁是伊莱恩？（与“路”谐音）
Who's Elaine?
小东尼泰山 用鼻毛荡来荡去
Little Tony Tarzan Swinging on a nose hair Swinging with the greatest of ease
不费吹灰之力
Swinging with the greatest of ease
我不知道怎么接
I don't know the next verse.
你可以唱“不费吹灰之力”
You could just go:Greatest of ease
然后接下去
Then go right into it.
也对，我喜欢
I like that.
慢着，你怎么会那个…
How do you know about...?
我玩过音乐
You know,I used to play.
也对，键盘嘛
That's right. The keyboards?
高中只是玩玩 大学才真正投入
A little in high school. I got into it in college.
那时我才找到我的声音
That's when I really found my sound.
我把果汁喷出来了，但是值得
Orange juice just came out of my nose,but it was worth it.
天哪，我都忘了你的声音
Oh,my God! I completely forgot about your sound.
他常把自己锁在地下室好久
He'd lock himself in the basement for hours.
谁也不准听那个“声音”
No one was ever allowed to hear the sound.
我想听那个“声音”
I want to hear the sound.
不行，我很久没弹了
No,I mean,I haven't played in so long.
那是很私密的东西
Well,it's really personal stuff.
快嘛，弹弹那些黑人爵士乐，白人男孩
Play that funky music,white boy.
是啊
-Yeah,come on.
不行啦，我的键盘在…
-No,you guys.My keyboards are all the way
好吧
Yeah,okay.
谁待会要跟我吃饭
Who wants to get dinner later?
我想去那家意大利餐厅 应该很不错
I wanna try that new ltalian restaurant.Supposed to be really good.
我看到里面有很多中国人
Saw a lot of Chinese people eating in there.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你常说某家餐厅一定很不错 里面有很多中国人
You said some restaurant must be good because Chinese people were eating there.
因为那是中国餐厅
That's because it was a Chinese restaurant.
我还是想去，谁要一起？
I still wanna go. Who wants to come?
我不行 我晚上有两个约会，所以…
Oh,I can't. I got two dinner dates tonight,so I gotta get ready.
我要去准备了
I gotta get ready.
好，就我们女生了
All right,girls' night out.
对不起 我们得准备明天的宴会
Sorry,but we have to prep that catering thing for tomorrow.
是啊 我希望我可以一个人吃饭
Oh,that's right.I wish I could eat in restaurants alone.
你应该试试看，那样蛮好的
You should try it. It's a really good thing to do.
我会浑身不对劲 好像自己是展示品
I just think I'd feel really self-conscious. Like I was on display or something.
我展示过 跟独自吃饭最像了
I was on display once. Nothing like eating alone.
我自己玩得很开心
I just had a great time with myself.
听起来是个很好的故事
Well,this could be a good story.
我是说吃饭
At dinner.
感觉好自由
It was so liberating.
我不需要别人给我乐趣
You know,I don't need people to have fun.
我能自得其乐 我是个有趣的女孩
I'm fun. I'm a fun girl.
你是个坏女孩吗？
Are you a naughty girl?
有趣就好，有趣，很好
No,just fun. Fun. Good. Fun.
我就说会很好玩吧 是啊
-See,I told you you'd have fun. -I know.
但我对自己吃饭的女生有偏见
Although I must say that I totally judge any woman I see eating alone.
为什么？ 很抱歉，自己吃饭有什么不对
-Why? -What's wrong with a woman eating alone?
当然有，她自己吃饭耶
Well,obviously something. She's eating alone.
可以了
Okay,guys.
好，来吧
All right! Bring it on,you!
开始了
Here we go.
我的东西没有弹给别人听过
You know,I've never played my stuff for anyone before.
希望你们能了解这是在传达…
So it's important that you understand...it's about communicating
很私密的情感
...very private emotions.
你们应该把我的作品
You know....You should think of my work...
看做是无字音诗
...as wordless sound poems.
意思是…上帝啊你就弹吧
-That's what -Oh,my God,play.
这真是…
Well,you know,that was...
太棒了（也有“吓人的”意思
...terrific!
真是…虐
Really...bitchen.
哇！我的天哪！
Wow! It was so wow!
真的吗？
Really?
对，你实在应该去表演
Yeah! I mean,you should play in public.
谢谢你们，这真是…
Wow,thanks,you guys. That's
我想再弹另一首
I want to play you another piece.
直升机音效在另一张光盘里 我马上回来
I left my helicopter sounds on another disk. I'll be right back,okay?
你们真是太好了，我好…
This is so nice. I mean,I am so....
幸好我爸替地下室隔音
God bless my dad for soundproofing the basement.
我居然让他用那些手指摸我
I can't believe I ever let him touch me with those fingers.
你们在说什么？我好喜欢
What are you guys talking about? I loved it!
太动人了
It was so moving.
而且跟一般听到的东西都不同
It's so different from the stuff you usually hear.
你是说音乐吗？
You mean,music?
我知道你在想什么
I know what you think.
好啦，你的胸部也很坚挺多汁
Yes,yes,your breasts are just as firm and juicy.
请进
Come in.
天哪，那是《海滩游侠》吗？
Oh,God! Is that Baywatch?
对，我只是为了写文章才要看的
Yes,but I just watch it for the articles.
乔伊在吗？
-So is Joey around?
他还没回来，应该马上就会到
-No,he's not back yet.
进来坐，船头还是船尾？
Come in,have a seat. Bow or stern?
我无所谓，你呢？
I don't have a preference. You?
我喜欢后面
I like it in the stern.
我是说船尾
Of the boat.
是我，听着 我们的车出了状况
It's me. Casey and l had a little car trouble.
怎么了？ 我们的车在路上坏了
-What happened? -We broke down.
我得走回去找变速器油
I have to get transmission fluid.
帮我跟凯西道歉 说我马上回去
Tell Kathy that I'm sorry and I'll be there soon.
你怎么不自己说？ 我只有一枚硬币，时间快要…
-Why can't you tell her? -I think my time is about to
乔伊？
Joey,Joey
怎样？
Ya!
我以为你时间到了
I thought your time ran out.
我也以为，看来还有一点…
Me too,but I guess I do have
乔伊会晚一点，他跟你道歉
Joey's running a little late,and he says he's sorry.
就剩我们两个了
I guess it's just you and me,then.
好 我想也是
-Okay. -Yeah,I think it is.
你今天做了什么？
So,what'd you do today?
我约好要去剪头发
I had an appointment to cut my hair.
很好 然后取消了
-Looks great! -And then it got canceled.
我可以帮你剪
-I could cut it.
真的吗？ 对
-Really? Do you do that?Yeah.
我是在姑妈的狗美容院学的 不过你要不要？
I learned at my aunt's dog-grooming shop. What do you say?
狗美容？
Dog grooming?
好，别把尾巴剪得太蓬
Don't make my tail too poofy.
你的发质很好
You have really great hair.
谢谢，我自己种的
Oh,thanks. I grow it myself.
乔伊的发质也很好
You know who also has great hair is Joey.
对，乔伊的发质很好
Yes,Joey has great hair.
差不多了，我帮你清一下
I'm basically done here. Let me get this hair off your neck.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
看一下长度是否一致 好
Checking to see if it's even.
看来没问题
Looks good.
电话！电话在发出声音
The phone! The phone's making sounds!
老兄，是我
Hey,dude,it's me.
是乔伊
Hey,it's Joey!
对不起，我们会拖上一阵子
It looks like we'll be stuck here.
我弄到机油了，但是要加油时
I got the fluid.
发现变速器不在
The transmission wasn't there.
什么？ 一定是掉了
-What? -It fell out.
我们撞到一只狗
I just figured we hit a dog.
好 请凯西来听，我要跟她道歉
Could you put Kathy on? I want to apologize to her.
好…乔伊找你
It's Joey.
没关系，放心好了
No,it's fine. Don't worry about it.
别再道歉了，没关系
Yeah,no,stop apologizing. It's okay.
好，明天再联络
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
我该走了 对，好
I should probably go.
我忘了带皮包
I forgot my purse.
我是真的忘了带皮包 我知道
I really did. I forgot my purse.
这样很不好
-This is bad! It's bad!
太糟糕了
-Horrible!
你是说吻还是状况？
Wait,the kiss or the situation?
不，那个吻很棒
The kiss was good.
但这样很不好 对，好，这样吧
-But that's bad! -Here's what we do.
我们忘了这件事 什么？
-We forget it happened. -What?
我们压抑我们的感觉
We swallow our feelings
即使这样会痛苦一辈子 不错吧？
Even if we're unhappy forever. Sound good?
你真的做得到？
Can you really do that?
我不得不 他是我最好的朋友
I have to. He's my best friend.
而你在跟他交往
And you're seeing him.
钱德，我很喜欢乔伊
Chandler,I like Joey a lot.
但是跟你…
-But with you
不，别说了
-No,don't! Don't,see?
你会把我搞乱 我已经开始渴望了
You're getting me confused. I'm starting to yearn.
对不起
I'm sorry.
要是你想假装没事 我可以试试看
If you want to pretend that nothing happened,I can try.
我们非这么做不可
I think we have to.
好
Okey.
再见 再见
Bye.-Bye.
你还在外面吗？
Are you still out there?
没有
NO.
振奋人心
Electrifying
无穷的时间
Infinite time
三条街外有一家星巴克
There's a Starbucks about three blocks down.
他的灵感好丰富，你们看他
He's so inspired. Just look at him. Look at him go!
谢谢各位
Thank you very much!
接着不是该你？
Hey,aren't you up next?
不，我今天不唱了 为什么？
-I'm not playing tonight. -Why not?
我不能接在罗斯后面
I can't follow Ross.
那就像骑脚踏车的猩猩 接在披头四后面一样，天哪
It'd be like those poor bicycle-riding chimps who had to follow the Beatles. No.
菲比，罗斯很烂
Ross sucks.
他把客人都吓跑了
The place has emptied because of him.
天哪，当世甚至没有人欣赏他
Oh,my God,he's not even appreciated in his own time.
我巴不得能跟他一样不被欣赏
I'd give anything to not be appreciated in my own time!
好，菲比…
Okey,Pheebe.
你也很烂
You suck too.
没错，菲比，你…烂透了
You're awful.
真是的
You guys!
你们也很烂
You suck too!
天哪 我居然又把自己锁在外面了
Man! I can't believe I locked myself out again!
等一下
Hang on,buddy.
天哪，出了什么事？
Oh,my God! What happened?
这都是你买的？ 就是我
-Did you do all this? Why? -I sure did.
为什么？ 我喜欢为我的朋友尽一点心
It made me feel good to do something nice for my friend.
你真好
You're amazing.
不，这个才叫好
No,this is amazing.
凭空冒出来的电视
A TV that appears as if from nowhere!
这是我的梦想
That's the dream!
你哪来这么多钱？
How did you afford all this?
我都29了，还存什么钱？
I'm 29. I mean,who needs a savings account?
你是世界上最棒的朋友
You're the best friend anyone has ever had.
我可不敢说
I don't know.
你是 你买这些东西，还给我忠告
No,you are.You do this,you give me advice....
对了，你不是要我定下来？
What you said about focusing on one woman?
我决定照做
I'll do that.
跟凯希？
With Casey?
不，我要跟凯西继续，她很酷
I'll see how things go with Kathy. She's cool.
或者凯希 不，凯西
-Or Casey. -No,Kathy.
凯希也行
-Could be Casey.
不，凯西
No,Kathy.
考虑一下凯希
Consider Casey.
看来有人在喜欢凯希喔
I think somebody's got a little crush on Casey.
要不要我帮你们牵线？
I'll fix you two up. What do you think?
那我这一生将了无遗撼
That all the pieces of my life are falling right into place.
你好厉害，真的真的好厉害
You were really great. You were really,really great.
谢谢
Thanks.
莫妮卡说你不想再表演了
Monica tells me you don't want to play anymore because of me...
因为我和我的才华
...and,you know,my talent.
是真的吗？
Is that true?
算是吧
Well,kind of,yeah.
我很想抱持无所谓乐观的态度
I was trying to be really okay and upbeat about it...
但是你的音乐才华令我自惭形秽
...but I just feel so dwarfed by your musical gift.
但是…
See,but....
菲比，这跟我做音乐的用意 正好相反
Pheebs,that is the exact opposite intent of my music.
我做音乐是想要启发人心
You know,my music is meant to inspire.
要是你这么困扰，那我…
If it bothers you this much...
我就不弹了
...then I won't play anymore.
不，千万不要
No,don't do that.
我怎么能让这个世界 失去你的音乐？
How could I live if I knew I was depriving the world of your music?
好吧
Yeah,okay.
我很想，但我星期天有事
-I'd love to,but I have plans on Sunday.
那就改天吧 好，打电话给我
-Well,maybe some other time.-Sure. Just give me a call,I'm in the book.
好，谢了，再见
-Okay. Thanks a lot. See you.
你在干什么？ 他很帅，又是医生
What are you doing? He is cute,and he's a doctor.
你怎么知道？
-How do you know?
亲爱的，因为我关心所以我偷听
-Honey,I eavesdrop because I care.
我星期天有约
-Well,I have plans on Sunday.
跟谁？ 我自己
-With who?-Me.
天哪
-Oh,God.
是你说独处很重要的
You are the one who told me how important it is to spend time alone.
我跟自己有约就不能跟他出去
I can't just go out with that guy when I have plans with myself.
那样对我不公平
Wouldn't be fair to me.
你是说你不想对自己不忠
So basically you're saying you don't want to cheat on yourself.
如果你要把我说成疯子的话
Well,if you wanna make me sound crazy.
新家具很棒喔
Saw the new furniture. Very nice.
乔伊有你这个男朋友真好
Joey has the best boyfriend ever!
我吻了凯西
I kissed Kathy.
真的还假的？
Are you serious?
乔伊知道吗？ 不知道
-Does Joey know? -No.
你们想他有可能谅解吗？
Is there any way you think he will understand this?
你显然没有背叛过朋友
You obviously haven't screwed over your friends.
我们都很感激
Which we all appreciate.
要是你先坦承你的感觉再亲她
If you'd told him how you felt before you kissed her...
乔伊一定会退让
...knowing Joey,he'd have stepped aside.
别这么说！这不是真的吧？
Don't say that! That's not true,is it?
真的啊 他爱你
Yeah,he loves you.
那你们怎么不告诉我？
Then why didn't you tell me to do that?
我跟菲比聊过
I said something to Phoebe.
对，我觉得这是个好主意。是的，我记得
And I thought it was a really good idea.-Yeah,I remember.
天哪！
-Oh,my God!
我该怎么办？
What am I going to do?
你得告诉他
-You'll have to tell him.
为什么我要告诉他？
-Why do I have to tell him?
你就是得说 我知道
-Because you do. -Yeah,I know.
我可以拿这件事写一首歌吗？
Would it be okay if I wrote a song about this?
我不知道这样下去行不行
I don't know if this is working out. I think....
我觉得…我想见其他人
I think I wanna see other people.
想不到会这样
Wow. Didn't see that coming.
不是我不喜欢这样，我喜欢
It's not that I don't enjoy this. I do.
我只是想看看其他可能性
I just wanna see what else is out there.
盖，你怎么会来这里？ 我刚从对街过来
Hey,Guy. What are you doing here?I work across the street.
你知道吗？结果我星期天有空
-lt turns out I'm gonna be free Sunday.
你应该早通知我 我刚同意周末加班
-I wish you had called me.I just told them I'd work this weekend.
好吧，那就下个周末
Okay,well,maybe next weekend.
没问题，到时候见 好
-Definitely. I'll see you. -Okay.
我不会再理你了 你是自己吃饭的怪人
Yeah,you'll be talking to me never,because you're a freak who eats alone.
茴香玛格丽特？
Sambuca margarita?
是真的吗？
It that a real thing?
我们只有茴香酒，所以是
Well,we only had sambuca,so it is now.
听着，乔伊，我有事要说
Listen,Joe. I need to I need to talk to you about something.
什么事？
What's up?
是凯西的事
It's about Kathy.
我喜欢她 其实是非常喜欢
I like her.I like her a lot,actually.
真的？ 对
-You do? -Yeah.
那你的时机正好 她不是我的女朋友了
Your timing couldn't be better.She's not my girlfriend anymore.
什么？
What?
她跟我分手了
-Yeah,she broke up with me.
什么时候？ 刚才上完表演课后
-When?Just now,after acting class.
我以为她在演戏，还让别人看
I thought she was doing some scene,so I let people watch.
太可惜了，你还好吗？
Man,I am so sorry. Are you okay?
好多了，我没事 你喜欢她？
I've been better,but I'm all right. So you like her?
对，但我不一定要喜欢她
Yes,but I don't have to.
不，没关系
No,it's okay.
真的？ 对，你知道为什么？
Yeah，You know why?
因为你先来告诉我
Because you came to me first.
我觉得这么做最好
I thought that would be the best thing to do.
你可能会很辛苦
You might have your work cut out for you.
我跟她谈的时候 觉得她在喜欢别人
When I talked to her,I got the feeling she's into some other guy.
这就是我要跟你谈的事
See,that's actually what I wanted to talk to you about.
我想我知道那个人是谁
I think I know who the other guy is.
是谁？
Who?
是我，我就是那个别人
It's me.I'm the other guy.
什么？
What?
对，你昨天晚归 凯西和我聊了起来
When you were late last night,Kathy and I got to talking...
事情演变到后来就…
...and one thing led to another,and....
就什么？你跟她上床？
And what? Did you sleep with her?
没有，我只是吻了她
-No,I just kissed her.
什么？那样更糟！
-What? That's even worse!
怎么会更糟？ 我不知道，反正都一样
-How is that worse? -I don't know.It's the same!
对不起，我也没办法 我爱上她了
There's nothing I could do. I think I'm in love with her!
那又怎样？
Who cares?
你背着我乱来？ 我绝不会那样对你
You went behind my back? I'd never do that to you!
你说得对，我无话可说 我完全过线了
I have no excuses. I was totally over the line.
完全过线？你根本就过线到
You're so far past the line,
你根本就没看到线 对你来说那条线只是个点
that you can't even see the line!The line is a dot to you!
没错，没错 我很自责，你要相信我
Yes,right! And I feel horrible. You have to believe me.
所以你买了这些东西？
Oh,my God. Is that why you bought all this stuff?
你知道吗？
You know what?
我不看你的电视 我不听你的音响
I will not watch your TV.I won't listen to your stereo.
烤面包机里有一个面包我不吃 你知道为什么？
And there's a loaf in the new bread maker I won't eat. Know why?
因为… 因为它被你的背叛弄脏了
-Probably because -It's all tainted with your betrayal!
今后这间房子对我而言是空的
This apartment is empty to me!
我对你也很不爽
I'm not happy about you either.
跟你说一声
And just so you know...
那个面包是为你烤的
...I made that bread for you.
天哪，他完全不行了
Oh,my God! He's lost it. He's totally lost it.
什么？
What?
菲比 他的音乐本来就烂到最高点
This cannot get any worse.
地下室的老鼠都去上吊了
Rats in the basement are hanging themselves.
谢谢
Thank you. Thanks.
我不行了
I lost it.
我再也不玩音乐了，你愿意…
I won't play anymore.Would you?
你可以完成我的事业吗？
Can you finish my set?
接着上台？可以
After that? Yeah.
我是说我愿意尽力
No,I mean,if I can help.
我怎么可能不行了
Yeah,like I could lose it.
什么？ 我是故意弹得很烂
What?I played bad on purpose,guys.
原来你一直都在故意
Okay,you were trying to play bad this whole time.
不，只有刚才那首
No. Just that last song.